Tyler Rhodes

Tylerlrhodes@gmail.com

website: https://www.tylerrhodes.net github: https://github.com/tylerlrhodes

631-560-5427

Summary:

Skilled Software Engineer and IT Professional with strong communication and organizational skills. Capable of handling projects large and small within software engineering and systems/network domains. Experience working with large and small organizations as both a consultant and employee.

Skills:

C#, JavaScript, Clojure, C/C++, Python, HTML, CSS, Databases (SQL Server, Postgres, Mongo, Redis), Web Applications, Web Security, Backend Software Engineering, Azure, AWS, Networking (TCP/IP, DNS, Firewalls, Switches, Routers), Basic DevOps, Windows, Linux, Mac OS

Experience:

Subway (Franchise World Headquarters)

Software Engineer II July 2019 – Present

Software Engineer on the Digital Development Team developing a widely used site used to distribute corporate communications of varying forms to employees and franchisees. Communicated across teams and organizations to implement solutions and solve problems.

- Lead an effort to rearchitect document storage for the site, moving from the original design of storing documents in SQL Server to storing them on Azure Blob Storage.
- Implemented a secure token signature system to secure access to videos hosted on a 3rd party platform.
- Identified and fixed security issues including access issues, CSRF and XSS issues.
- Replaced a 3rd party SharePoint integration system which was to become obsolete with a custom-tailored solution without the unnecessary complexity.

Bernoulli Enterprise Inc. (Now Capsule Technologies)

Software Engineer October 2017 – July 2019

Full Stack developer with a focus on .NET working on the design and implementation of new features for leading medical integration and clinical surveillance software.

- Designed and implemented an add-on software component to the core system to facilitate the transfer of medical information to an EMR system such as Epic through HL7. Implemented as a .NET service with a web component to view the status.
- Implemented an interface for the TAP protocol which allows paging systems in Hospitals to send messages and alerts through Bernoulli Software to other alerting systems.
- Participated in bug fixes and customer support as needed. Provided guidance to junior engineers.

FUJIFILM Medical Systems USA Inc.

Systems Integration Engineer / Software Engineer November 2013 – October 2017

Worked within two teams in a cross-functional role addressing software development and field issues. Participated in many aspects of software development including design and implementation of new features, bug fixes, updates to existing code, and testing.

- Work on the DICOM Standards Group and Solutions Delivery Team as an intermediary to develop new features which overlap with the Standards Group and Database Team, as well as address field issues related to Standards within the software.
- Designed and implemented a system for collecting and reporting on key metrics integrated into the overall product. Consisting of an IIS Native Module (C++), a simple ASP Web API, and a JavaScript test harness, the system was flexible enough to support a variety of potential sources of metrics which could be sent using a custom COM component or sent directly using the network protocol or web API.
- Updated on numerous occasions a utility written in C++ which converted our proprietary file format to a standardized format to work with new updates to the proprietary file.
- Extended middleware database layer access component to support new functionality and queries, involving C# and a CQRS data access pattern and PL/SQL updates to Oracle database.
- Implement new "Pages/Tools" for the software's web-based administration site. Depending on the area this is done using either a Node.js based framework, or a classic ASP based framework.

Open Doors Technology

Network Consultant June 2010 – November 2013

Worked as a consultant stationed onsite at two clients located on Long Island and provided IT services to other clients remotely as needed.

Responsible for designing, managing and deploying customer networks. Managed and
implemented software such as VMware vSphere, Citrix VDI-In-A-Box, Exchange Server (multiple
versions), Windows Server and Active Directory. Managed and deployed network infrastructure
including switches, routers, firewalls and wireless access points. Implemented iSCSI storage
from Dell and EqualLogic.

- Designed and implemented a custom CRM solution using PHP, HTML, JavaScript and CSS from the ground up for a client. Designed and coded the database backend using a MySQL database server.
- As part of a prototype project designed and implemented an iPhone application which
 communicated with an XML web service to retrieve data for display. Also assisted with the
 development of a customized piece of hardware which was to feed data to a database from
 which the mobile application would retrieve the data. Basic prototyping was done with an
 Arduino and some sample scale hardware which interfaced through a breadboard.
- Supported large and small clients on all types of software and hardware including Windows and Mac.

Global Computer Systems

Systems Integrator April 2007 – February 2010, 2003-2003

Multiple roles supporting clients and providing IT services.

- Participated in all aspects of information systems operations, including the design, support, maintenance, documentation and management of many different networks of varying sizes and complexities. Managed multiple ongoing projects and concurrently handled incoming customer requests. Consulted with IT directors and managers to make recommendations on technical matters.
- Designed, managed, and implemented multiple projects upgrading clients IT infrastructure including core components such as firewalls, switches, routers, servers, Active Directory, Exchange, Phone Systems and other software.
- Developed a basic accounting software in C# with an Access Database backend. Supported multiple users.

Education:

Coursework at Marist, Georgia Military College, and Empire State College

A+ Certification

Expired CCDA